# Preet K. Shah

Front-end Developer & Aspiring Full-stack Web Developer | Newcastle Upon Tyne, UK Email: <a href="mailto:shahpreetk@outlook.com">shahpreetk@outlook.com</a> | LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/shahpreetk/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/shahpreetk/</a> | Website: <a href="https://shahpreetk.github.io">https://shahpreetk.github.io</a>

#### **Summary**

A self-taught web developer with experience in MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js). An enthusiastic individual with a leadership mindset, I always look forward to learning new technologies in the field of Full-stack Development. Currently pursuing a Masters in Computer Science from Newcastle University, UK (graduating in September 2022) and working as a Software Development Engineer at J.P. Morgan Chase.

#### **Skills**

- HTML & CSS
- Javascript
- React
- Node.js
- Express.js
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- Java Object Oriented Programming
- Java Spring Boot
- CSS Frameworks: Tailwind CSS | Bootstrap | react-bootstrap | reactstrap | daisyUI
- API Testing tool: Postman & Hoppscotch.io
- Deployment: Netlify | Surge | Heroku | GitHub Pages
- Firebase
- Git & Github
- Next.js
- React Native
- Redux
- Ionic 5 with react.js
- Microsoft Office Microsoft Word, Excel, Powerpoint
- Google Office Suite Google Docs, Sheets, Slides, Forms
- Figma & Adobe XD designing UI for websites
- Procreate & Canva Digital Art and Design
- Public Speaking & Leadership
- Volunteering

# **Work Experience**

# **Software Development Engineer**

JPMorgan Chase & Co., UK

• Training in the Tech Connect program

July 2022 - Present

# **Intern in MLH Fellowship**

Major League Hacking

September 2020 – December 2020

- Developed front-end for full-stack web applications.
- Designed UI for native mobile applications.

# Intern for UI/UX Designing, Front-end Development

Hellbent Software & Educational Services LLP

November 2019 – April 2020

- Designed and later developed the front-end of an Order Management System(with chat functionality).
- Implemented the front-end using HTML, CSS, and vanilla javascript.
- Freelanced for Hellbent as a front-end developer for 3 months.

#### **Education**

# **MSc in Computer Science**

Newcastle University, UK

September 2021 - Present

- Relevant subjects taught till May 2022
  - o CSC8011 Introduction to Software Development (Java Introduction) [Scored 87/100]
  - o CSC8012 Software Development Techniques and Tools (Java Intermediate) [Scored 93/100]
  - o CSC8014 Software Development Advanced Techniques (Java III) [Scored 100/100]
  - o CSC8015 Cybersecurity [Scored 91/100]
  - o CSC8016 Advanced Programming (Java IV) [Scored 87/100]
  - o CSC8017 Database Systems [Scored 92/100]
  - o CSC8018 Web Technologies [Scored 92/100]
  - o CSC8021 Computer Networks *[Scored 97/100]*
  - CSC8022 Human Computer Interaction [Scored 78/100]
- Predicted to graduate with 2:1 degree

# **Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Telecommunication**

K.J. Somaiya Institute of Engineering & IT (University of Mumbai)

July 2017 - June 2021

- Average GPA 7.48/10 CGPA (68.46%).
- Chairperson of the IETE Committee in 2020 2021.
- Assistant Leader of National Service Scheme, the University of Mumbai in 2019-2020.

## **Projects**

## **Trippy Castle**

- This was a team project made for a module in my Masters degree course.
- Successfully completed 6/6 basic requirements and 2/5 advanced requirements.
- Frontend GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/shahpreetk/trippycastle">https://github.com/shahpreetk/trippycastle</a>

#### **BookIt**

- Designed and developed an Online Auditorium and Turf booking system for degree college.
- The project was built using React.js in the front-end, Node.js as the server, MongoDB for the database and is hosted on Netlify.
- Integrated Stripe as a payment gateway.
- Published a paper in International Journal for Research in Applied Science & Engineering Technology (IJRASET) ISSN: 2321-9653; IC Value: 45.98; SJ Impact Factor: 7.429 Volume 9 Issue IV Apr 2021.
- Project URL: <a href="https://kjsieit-onlinebooking.netlify.app/">https://kjsieit-onlinebooking.netlify.app/</a>

#### **MLH Fellowship**

- Developed 6 projects on six themes like education, productivity, social good, gaming, machine learning and an open-ended theme.
- Won 3rd place for Knight in the Night game built using Godot engine.
- Worked on the front-end (React) for Mentored a mentor-mentee communication platform built using the MERN stack.
- Designed the UI for Volunteery a tinder-like application for NGOs built using Flutter which won 2nd place in the fellowship competition.
- Devpost URL <a href="https://devpost.com/shahpreetk">https://devpost.com/shahpreetk</a>

#### **Volunteer Work**

- Was elected as *Chief Website Officer* for Leo Multiple 3231(July 2020 June 2021).
- President of Leo District 3231 A1(July 2020 June 2021), Vice-President of Leo District 3231 A1(July 2019 June 2020).
- President of Leo Club of Walkeshwar(July 2019 June 2020).
- Oversaw the functioning of 7 clubs under the district & conducted Fellowship and Service events in my role as the District President.
- Received International President's Certificate of Appreciation from Lions Clubs International.

# **Online Course Certifications**

- MOOC Java Programming (in-progress) by *University of Helsinki*
- CS50 by *Harvard University*
- The Web Developer Bootcamp and MySQL Bootcamp by Colt Steele on Udemy

# Languages known

- English Scored 8.0/9.0 in IELTS
- Indian Hindi Native
- Gujarati Native

#### **Hobbies**

- Painting & Digital Art
- Reading crime fiction novels